http://www.bhcc.mass.edu/about/privacypolicy/

About Home
Achieving the DreamArt GalleryBHCC Foundation, Inc.BHCC Magazine -Spring 2020Board of TrusteesCampus Guests and VisitorsCharlestown CampusChelsea CampusCollege GoalsContactDirectoryEquity, Diversity & InclusionFacilities UpdatesFaculty and Staff ResourcesHuman ResourcesInstitutional EffectivenessInstitutional Learning OutcomesMission & VisionNewsOffice of the PresidentPartnerships & GrantsPrivacy PolicyPublic RecordsPublic SafetySatellite LocationsStrategic PlansSustainabilityTeaching & Learning InstituteWeb Accessibility
Academics Home
Academic CalendarAcademic ResourcesAccreditationBHCC BookstoreBoston Welcome Back CenterCollege CatalogCommonwealth Honors ProgramCourse SchedulesDepartmentsDivisionsEnglish Language Learning ProgramsLearning CommunitiesLibraryOpen Educational Resources (OER) InitiativePrograms of StudySelf-Directed Learning
Admissions Home
Accepted StudentsAdult LearnerAdvising & Registration & OrientationApply NowAssessment CenterBHCC Virtual CampusCity of Boston Free Tuition ProgramDual EnrollmentGuest StudentsInformation SessionsInternational AdmissionsMini SessionsOnline Winter Session 2021Paying for CollegeTransfer in to BHCCTransfer PartnershipsUndocumented & DACA Students
Student Life Home
Advising & LifeMapAthleticsBankMobile RefundsBHCC ChatCampus DiningCareer AdvisingCommunity EngagementCounseling, Prevention and WellnessDisability Support ServicesDISH Food PantryHealth ServicesInternships and Career DevelopmentmyBHCCShuttle ScheduleSingle StopStudent Affairs-Dean of Students OfficeStudent CentralStudent ClubsStudent HandbookStudent Leadership and EngagementTechnology ResourcesTransfer ServicesVeterans Center
Initiatives Home
AANAPISIAlumni AssociationBasic NeedsCenter for Equity and Cultural WealthGeneral Education InitiativeGrants DevelopmentHalting Oppressive Pathways through EducationStudent Emergency Fund
Workforce Home
Community Education and Adult Learning PathwaysCorporate Learning & Professional DevelopmentTraining Opportunities (TOP) and MassHire TrainingWorkforce and Community Education Course CatalogBook Purchase
About
Achieving the Dream
Art Gallery
About the Gallery
Residency
Residency 2018-2019 - Robin Chandler
About the Artist and Scholar
In the Artist's Words
Exhibit Catalog
BHCC Distinguished Artist Scholar in Residence
Previous Exhibits
Events
Visit
Exhibition Policy
BHCC Foundation, Inc.
Foundation News
Opportunities for Giving
BHCC Foundation Board of Directors
Gala
Amazon Smile
Run for BHCC
Foundation Scholars
BHCC Magazine -Spring 2020
Richard Dreyfuss
Harold E. Ford, Jr.
Mary Frances Berry
Laila Ali
Frank H. Wu
Mary Robinson
Felipe Luciano
Nathan McCall
Barbara Ehrenreich
Ray Suarez
Pregnant Workers Fairness Act
Equity Work Group (EWG)
BHCC Campus Climate Survey
Facilities Updates
Faculty and Staff Resources
Institutional Review Board
Integrated Marketing & Communications
Awards
BHCC Logo and Mascot Usage
College Logo Usage
Student Learning Outcomes Assessment Program
Why Do We Use Student Learning Outcomes?
How Do You Create Student Learning Outcomes?
Tools and Resources
Associate in Arts Degrees
Associate in Science Degrees
Certificate Programs
Selective Program Instructions
Courses
General Education Requirements
Gen Ed Requirements before Fall 2019
Emergency Studies
Emergency Medical Technician (EMT)
Paramedic Studies Certificate & Associate Degree
Employment Opportunities
Program Outcomes
Degrees and Certificates
Courses
Nurse Education
Courses
Degrees and Certificates
The Writing Place
English Language Learning (ELL)
ELL Courses
Mission Statement
Frequently Asked Questions
Global Languages Department
Why Study a Global Language
Global Language Faculty
Useful Links
Courses
Tell - Digital Literary Magazine
Textbook Assistance Program (TAP)
Open Educational Resources (OER) Initiative
Programs of Study
Self-Directed Learning
Admissions
Accepted Students
Adult Learner
Advising & Registration & Orientation
Virtual Orientation
BHCC Cares Challenge
Community Work Study Program (CWS)
Honor Students In Action
Jumpstart
Service Months
Community Organizations
Talking Politics
Counseling, Prevention and Wellness
Disability Support Services
Disability Documentation Guidelines
1098T Frequently Asked Questions
Automatic Payment Plan (ACI Payments, Inc.)
Waivers
International Payments
Payments
Refunds
Terms and Conditions
Registration & Financial Responsibility
Health Insurance
BHCC ID Card
Academic and Career Resources
Student Veterans Organization (SVO)
Faculty/Staff Resources
Additional Resources
Contact Us
Veterans Day Event
Initiatives
AANAPISI
Year 1 Summary Report
Year 2 Summary Report
Exhibition Policy
BHCC Foundation, Inc.
Foundation News
Opportunities for Giving
BHCC Foundation Board of Directors
Gala
Amazon Smile
Run for BHCC
Foundation Scholars
BHCC Magazine -Spring 2020Board of Trustees
Richard Dreyfuss
Harold E. Ford, Jr.
Mary Frances Berry
Laila Ali
Frank H. Wu
Mary Robinson
Felipe Luciano
Nathan McCall
Barbara Ehrenreich
Ray Suarez
Pregnant Workers Fairness Act
Equity Work Group (EWG)
BHCC Campus Climate Survey
Facilities UpdatesFaculty and Staff Resources
Institutional Review Board
Integrated Marketing & Communications
Awards
BHCC Logo and Mascot Usage
College Logo Usage
Athletics Mascot Usage
Bunker Hill Community College Privacy Policy
This privacy policy has been updated to comply with General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR).
Bunker Hill Community College maintains this website at bhcc.edu and the official BHCC Mobile App to provide information to you about the College, its policies, campuses, facilities and programs. This privacy policy explains our online information practices for the Site and App.
We may automatically collect and store information sent by your web browser, such as IP addresses or geolocations in server logs. We also collect standard information about your computer (such as your web browser and operating system) and about your usage of our websites and digital properties (such as pages visited, length of visit, and search queries). This information, which does not identify you personally, is aggregated and used to help diagnose problems and suggest points for improving parts of our website and digital properties.
We and our third-party partners use cookies to monitor and analyze web traffic and to keep track of user behavior and demographics. One such service that we may use for this purpose is Google Analytics.
You may provide us with personally identifying information through electronic forms or emails and we may use this data to send you information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions. When you complete an electronic form, you may be asked to enter your name, email address, mailing address, phone number, or other details. We collect this information and use it for internal College purposes, including to send you information about the College, respond to your questions and requests, administer College events, gather statistical information about prospective students and website or mobile app users, and other similar purposes.
Bunker Hill Community College does not sell, rent, give away, or loan any personally identifiable information collected on the website or mobile app to any third party for commercial purposes. We may use such information, or share such information with our third party partners, for internal College purposes, such as to provide and improve our services or communications to users. We may also provide your information to third parties in circumstances where we believe that doing so is necessary or appropriate : as required by law; to prevent or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Bunker Hill Community College , our users, or others.
In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. No method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage, however, is 100% secure.
The website and/or mobile app may contain links to other websites of interest. Bunker Hill Community College does not control third-party websites and is not responsible for the privacy practices or contents of any linked website.
Personally Identifying Information and/or Personal Information
1. What is “personal information”?
“Personal information” means any information which relates to or identifies you as an individual including, but are not limited to, name, email, phone numbers, IP address, photo, and educational, financial, employment-related, and health data.
2. What does it mean to “process” personal information?
Processing is any operation performed on personal information, such as collecting, destroying, recording, organizing, storing, altering, or disclosing.
3. What personal information will be processed?
BHCC will process the information you provide when you request additional information from the BHCC and/or submit your admission application together with the supporting documents requested to complete your application.
4. What is the purpose and legal basis of the processing?
BHCC will process your personal information for the purposes of identifying you, processing your request for information or application for admission, verifying the information provided, reaching an admission decision, and communicating that outcome and/or other feedback.  BHCC may also process your information for the following statutory obligations, contractual necessity and/or public interest purposes:
To confirm immigration status;
For affirmative action and equal opportunity monitoring;
To prevent or detect fraud or other criminal activity;
To confirm elementary and secondary education record;
To assist in providing reasonable accommodations for a disability;
To provide information as required by applicable law; and
For research and statistical purposes, but only in a non-identifiable, aggregate format.
Admission decisions are made on a case-by-case basis and are not the result of automated decision-making.
5. Who will process my personal information?
For the purposes stated above, during the admission process your personal information will be processed by and shared with the following:
Admissions Office;
Financial Aid Office;
International Studies Office;
Student Services Office;
Registrar’s Office;
Disability Services if an accommodation is requested;
Institutional Research;
Student and Exchange Visitor Program Designated School Official;
Governmental bodies when required by law;
State authorities in order to perform one or more statutory duties; and
Third-parties providing specific services to, or on behalf of, the College.
BHCC may subsequently identify other departments or external parties who will process your personal information as you progress through the application process.
6. How is my personal information used if I am accepted?
Once you are accepted and begin attending BHCC, your personal information is no longer covered by the GDPR.  As a student at BHCC, your personal information shall be processed in accordance with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (“FERPA”), a U.S. federal law.  To learn about your rights under FERPA, please visit  https://www2.ed.gov/policy/gen/guid/fpco/ferpa/index.htm.  If your acceptance to the College is for an on-line course or program only, and you remain in an EU member state while participating in the course or program, the GDPR shall continue to apply to the processing of your personal information.
7. How long is my personal information kept?
BHCC shall retain and store personal information in accordance with applicable U.S., state, and federal law.  If you are accepted, your personal information will be kept as part of your student record for the duration of your studies and, where applicable, a prescribed period of time thereafter.
If you are unsuccessful, your information will be normally kept for at least 2 years after the completion of the application process.
Accessing Your Personal Information
How can I access my personal information?
You have the right to access the personal information that is held about you by BHCC.  You also have the right to ask BHCC to correct any inaccurate personal information it holds about you.  In order to access your personal information, please contact admissions@bhcc.edu
Who can I contact if I have any questions?
If you have any questions about this policy statement, BHCC’s compliance with the GDPR, or the processing of your personal information, please contact GDPR@bhcc.edu
How do I report a complaint?
If BHCC fails to adequately address your concerns, you also have a right to file a complaint with the Massachusetts Department of Higher Education at: https://www.mass.edu/forstufam/complaints/complaints.asp.
Policy Statement Updates
This policy statement was issued on September 21, 2018.  It will be reviewed as necessary and at least annually. Any changes to the policy will be posted on BHCC’s website located at bhcc.edu.
